The story that won't go away.
JFK is a drama, thriller, history film directed by Oliver Stone.
Follows the investigation into the assassination of President John F.
Kennedy led by New Orleans district attorney Jim Garrison.
Jim Garrison, played by Kevin Costner.
Clay Shaw, played by Tommy Lee Jones.
Lee Harvey Oswald, played by Gary Oldman.
Willie O'Keefe, played by Kevin Bacon.
Bill Broussard, played by Michael Rooker.
Jack Martin, played by Jack Lemmon.
JFK is a 1991 American epic political thriller film
co-written and directed by Oliver Stone.
The film examines the investigation into the assassination of John F.
Kennedy by New Orleans district attorney Jim Garrison, who came to believe there was a
government conspiracy to assassinate Kennedy and that Lee Harvey Oswald was a scapegoat.
The film's screenplay was adapted by Stone and Zachary Sklar from the books On the Trail of the
Assassins by Garrison and Crossfire: The Plot That Killed Kennedy by Jim Marrs.
Stone described this account as a "counter-myth" to the
Warren Commission's "fictional myth".
JFK's embrace of conspiracy theories made it controversial.
Many major American newspapers ran editorials accusing Stone of spreading untruths, including the claim
that Kennedy was killed as part of a coup d'état to install Vice President Lyndon B.
Johnson in his place.
Despite the controversy, JFK received critical praise for its
performances, directing, score, editing, and cinematography.
It also gradually picked up momentum at the box office after a slow start, grossing over $205 million worldwide,
making it the sixth highest-grossing film of 1991 worldwide and Stone's highest-grossing film to date.
It was nominated for eight Academy Awards, including Best Picture, and
won two for Best Cinematography and Best Film Editing.
It was the first of three films Stone made about American
presidents, followed by Nixon (1995) and W.
The film explores themes of vietnam war, central intelligence
agency (cia), assassination, usa president, government.
The tone is emotional and intense.